<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>firefox on Joone Blog</title>
    <link>https://joone.github.io/tags/firefox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in firefox on Joone Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Joone Hur</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 23:04:56 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joone.github.io/tags/firefox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the &lt;aside&gt; Element in Web Accessibility: Standards, Challenges, and Cross-Browser Compatibility</title>
      <link>https://joone.github.io/posts/aside_aria/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 23:04:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joone.github.io/posts/aside_aria/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;lt;aside&amp;gt; element The &amp;lt;aside&amp;gt;element is typically used for displaying additional information that complements the main content.
https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/aside
How is the &amp;lt;aside&amp;gt;element handled in the accessibility tree? Each HTML element has a specific role in the accessibility tree, helping users in navigating content via assistive tools like VoiceOver. For example, the &amp;lt;aside&amp;gt;element assumes a complementary role in the Accessibility Tree.
However, in certain exceptional cases, the &amp;lt;aside&amp;gt;element does not assume this complementary role.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox4 &amp; the future of the Web</title>
      <link>https://joone.github.io/posts/firefox4-future-of-web_22/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 02:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joone.github.io/posts/firefox4-future-of-web_22/</guid>
      <description>Firefox4 was released last month. It has been downloaded more than 57 million times since its release from all over the world. The release has been successful so far, but it seems not to be easy to compete the other browsers as much as before. In this post, I am going to talk about new features of Firefox4 , the reason why using Firefox is important, and the task of remaining competitive as a community supported browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox for Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>https://joone.github.io/posts/firefox-for-mobile-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2008 05:55:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joone.github.io/posts/firefox-for-mobile-devices/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to share a little bit old presentation about Mobile Firefox.
From: mobileportland, 2 months ago
Firefox For Mobile Devices
view presentation (tags: browsers mozilla portland firefox)
Dietrich Ayala&amp;rsquo;s presentation at May 2008 meeting of Mobile Portland
SlideShare Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox&#43; Summit</title>
      <link>https://joone.github.io/posts/firefox-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 06:22:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joone.github.io/posts/firefox-summit/</guid>
      <description>I attended Firefox+ Summit at Whistler, Canada. It was a great time in my life because I met Mozilla folks who I had known the name only and talk about some issues I have wondered.
This occasion was held to celebrate Firefox3 release and talk about the future plan of Firefox3.1 and the current issues.
About 400 Mozilla peoples joined the summit coming from all over the World. They are involved in the various projects such as AMO(Add-ons), QA, Localization, Gecko, JavaScript, Mobile, UX, evangelist, messaging, SVG, MDC, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Camera Interface on Mobile Platform</title>
      <link>https://joone.github.io/posts/camera-interface-in-maemo-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2008 06:36:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joone.github.io/posts/camera-interface-in-maemo-platform/</guid>
      <description>Mozilla platform is trying to support device APIs for mobile environment.
Some people call them native interface
I already posted a blog on device APIs
The Mozilla community started to discuss what the device APIs should be supported through the news group and Mozilla wiki.
Christopher added some information regarding the device APIs in the wiki.
So you can find on-going issues to support the device APIs. They are not confirmed, so you can suggest your idea &amp;amp; opinion to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to support native interfaces on the Web</title>
      <link>https://joone.github.io/posts/how-to-support-native-interfaces-on-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2008 08:17:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://joone.github.io/posts/how-to-support-native-interfaces-on-web/</guid>
      <description>I posted an article about supporting native interfaces in Mobile Firefox. Byt the way, I found information regarding my post from here. This paper explained the native interfaces I talked as sensors on device and introduced how to send their sensed data to servers via the Web.
The sensor means a device that reads data from the user&amp;rsquo;s physical environment. By the way, I am interested in how to get data from the native interfaces via web browser.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
